the new zealand shooter left behind a
detailed record of his anti-immigrant
anti-muslim rhetoric and unfortunately
these days this kind of intolerance is
being tolerated in more places than you
might think
take a look
you have to try really really hard to
not see the rising tide of white
nationalism anti-immigrant and
anti-muslim sentiment around the globe
in preparation for the migrants the
border is being hardened
ultra-conservative anti-immigrant
parties are on the ride
so trump's not the only one inventing
border emergencies and talking about
walls
i was shocked to hear that the prick
allegedly behind the christchurch new
zealand mass shootings is a white
supremacist who grew up and was
radicalised
in australia
so what is the situation down there and
what are the people who may have
radicalised him saying unfortunately
what i found here was a lot like
charlottesville a lot of fringe
activists spouting anti-immigration
racist out in the open if you
want to fight islam you have to hit it
at the top get rid of that smug smile
go back to sudan white people
like myself feel happy and safe around
my culture my people and this
anti-immigration fervor is uniting some
strange groups it turns out that the one
thing that can bring together the
alt-right and a jew is their shared
hatred of muslims meet jewish activists
avi yami a good australian name islamic
immigration cut it no more issues no no
more muslims get rid of uh african
tribal anyone from africa what about
south africans
i think we should allow the white south
african farmers what about the black
south africans
i'll take that as a no what about
syrians those who are not going to
import a violent culture
how do you pick that out you all right
questions is that simple are you violent
no you're muslim we can't live in a
society where we go
this race can't be in in our country
absolutely we can now what makes avi
suddenly feel so comfortable saying this
out loud well just like in america
more and more australian officials are
comfortable saying this out loud
now we are in danger of being swamped by
muslims and right after the new zealand
shooting senator fraser anning blamed
the victims saying the real cause of the
shooting is the immigration program that
allowed muslim fanatics to migrate to
new zealand in the first place and then
the opposition responded
so even in australia conservatives are
taking a page out of trump's playbook
ginning up fear of immigrants it's very
dangerous out there drugs are pouring in
and clinging to one overly simplistic
idea walls work they work proven i think
it's a big waste of money powerful new
video shows more than 100 migrants
climbing over the border wall apparently
the smuggler had a ladder
look people come by
both by plane through tunnels and 62 of
new undocumented immigrants are just
people who overstayed a visa
immigration is way more complicated than
building a five billion dollar wall
have i been benefiting from a wall
my entire life i just found out that
australia is home to the largest
migration fence in the world so i'm off
to the outback to investigate i come
from a land down that uh
i don't know all the loots
[Music]
the fence is around 5
500 kilometers long that's way longer
than america's southern border
to learn more about this enormous
immigrant net i arranged to meet carl
who maintains the fence out here in this
dangerous borderland
jeff you're going kale good day carl you
take care of this fence
part of it and uh what immigrants you're
trying to stop from getting you know
assume somalians or some some type of
boat people probably be asians they're
sneaky nimble bunch that could jump over
with their gymnastics or whatnot luckily
enough for you you don't have mexicans
here you don't know the pain that the
americans have to feel on a constant
basis so so what immigrants are you
keeping out
none mate just dingoes
singles
bingo
that's right a bingo fence australians
build a man-made wonder to keep dingoes
from wandering about animal expert emma
malik explains
enjoying those flies there no it's a
horrible country thank god i've become
an american citizen i can't bear this
what's the history of the ding offense
so the reason why a fence was built was
protect the cattle and sheep you see
sheep are pretty dumb and they run at
anything and dingos love to chase so
they'll just kill pretty much a whole
flock they'll just kill it for the joy
of killing they just it's instinct
that's right innocent white victims
their communities invaded by violent
killers so the government had no choice
but to build a wall
but the walls work do the dingo still
get through oh they do they come over
here they're taking our jobs
they're taking our babies i haven't seen
a good one yet yeah yeah yeah they're
only good one's a dead one
like that yes
and once they get in you can't get rid
of them some refuse to assimilate living
by their own set of laws others get lazy
living off the fat of the land and they
take whatever they want would you say
that the dingoes who come over the
border bringing crime they're raping we
still talk about dingoes
i might sound like a hippie saying this
what gives anyone the right to tell
anyone where they can and can't live
when you import this culture what do you
think is going to happen australia's
going to end up the same that
they came from that they were escaping
and you see that across europe so what
countries have become shitholes france
france is a now absolutely the
germans took a million refugees
shitholes didn't they feel that way
about the jews they had to get rid of
the jews because they thought the place
was a
no but they did that makes sense you
don't understand you don't get it
do you feel lucky to be born into
australia absolutely because you could
have been born into what you called one
of these countries if you look
at the polls in australia done by the
polls get them out of here
oh the actual polls do whites ever do
anything wrong
statistically say in america there's way
more homegrown terrorists than there are
islamic terrorists i think you're nuts
you all believe in fairy tales
i'll tell you a fairy tale if you think
all this overheated rhetoric about
immigrants doesn't have real
consequences then you're ignoring
reality
hate crimes against latinos are on the
rise and 50 people were killed in new
zealand because a deranged
became convinced that muslim lives are
worth less
words matter
so think about that instead of focusing
on some pointless wall we've got wall in
israel yep china had a one it was great
right we have one in australia ding a
fence we went to the dingo is that a
wall though that's a fence it's the
longest fence in the world the dingoes
are still getting through they're still
getting through they're finding a way do
you think that's that's working i don't
know i don't live in the outback you
should there's loads of white people
that you'd love it
they hate you
you